<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for the more speedy and effectual proceeding upon distresses and avovvries for rent Chap. XXII.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A87306</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I320</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R43653</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">42475061</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 42475061</idno>
            <idno type="VID">151186</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A87306)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 151186)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2248:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for the more speedy and effectual proceeding upon distresses and avovvries for rent Chap. XXII.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Andrew Crook ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Chap. 22 of: Acts and statutes made in a Parliament begun at Dublin the twenty seaventh day of August, anno Dom. 1695 ... Dublin : printed by Andrew Crook ..., 1697.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: William Andrews Clark Memorial Library, University of California, Los Angeles.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Rent --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Landlord and tenant --  Law and legislation --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:151186:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
            <p>AN ACT For the more Speedy and Effectual Proceeding upon DISTRES<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>SES and AVOVVRIES for RENT.</p>
            <figure>
               <head>W R</head>
               <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <q>IE MEIN TIENDRAI</q>
               <figDesc>Royal blazon</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>D<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>BLIN,</hi> Printed by <hi>Andrew Crook,</hi> Printer to the Kings Moſt Excellent Majeſty, on <hi>Ormonde-Key,</hi> 1695.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="act">
            <pb facs="tcp:151186:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:151186:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
            <head>CHAP. XXII. An Act for the more Speedy and Effectual Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding upon Diſtreſſes and Avowries for Rent.</head>
            <p>FORASMUCH as the Ordinary Remedy for Arrearages of Rents is by Diſtreſs upon the Lands Chargeable therewith; and yet Nevertheleſs by reaſon of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tricate and Dillatory proceédings upon Reple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vin, that Remedy is become Ineffectual. For Remedy whereof,</p>
            <p>Be it Enacted by the King's Moſt Excellent Majeſty, with the Advice and Conſent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons in this preſent Parliament Aſſembled, and by Authority of the ſame, That whenever any Plantiff in Replevin ſhall be Non-Suit before Iſſue Ioyned in any Suit in Replevin, by Plaint or Writt Lawfully Returned, Removed, or Depending in any of His Majeſties Courts at <hi>Dublin,</hi> or any Courts Palatine, or other Courts of Record within this Kingdom. That the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant Avowant making a Suggeſtion in Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of an Avowry or Connuſance for ſuch Rent, to Aſcertain the Court of the Cauſe of Diſtreſs, the Court upon his Prayer ſhall Award a Writt to the Sheriff of the County where the Diſtreſs was taken, to Inquire by the Oaths of Twelve Good and Lawful Men of the Baliwick, touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Summ in Arrear at the time of ſuch Diſtreſs taken, and the value of the Goods or Cattle Diſtrained, and thereupon Notice of Fifteén Days ſhall be given to the Plantiff, or his Attorney
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:151186:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->
in Court of the Sitting of ſuch Inquiry, and thereupon the Sheriff ſhall Inquire of the Truth of the matter Contained in ſuch Writt, by the Oaths of Twelve Good and Lawful Men of his County; and upon the Return of ſuch Inquiſition the Defendant ſhall have Iudgment to Recover againſt the Plantiff the Arrearages of ſuch Rent, in Caſe the Goods or Cattle Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrained ſhall amount unto the Value; and in Caſe they ſhall not amount to that Value, then ſo much as the Value of the ſaid Goods and Cattle ſo Diſtrained ſhall amount unto, together with his full Coſts of Suit, and ſhall have Execution thereupon by <hi>Fieri facias,</hi> or <hi>Elegit,</hi> or otherwiſe, as the Law ſhall Require: And in Caſe ſuch Plantiff ſhall be Nonſuite, after Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuzance or Avowry made, and Iſſue Ioyned, or if the Verdict ſhall be given againſt ſuch Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff, then the Iurors that are Impannelled or Returned to Inquire of ſuch Iſſue ſhall at the Prayer of the Defendant Inquire concerning the Summ of the Arrears, and the Value of the Goods or Cattle Diſtrained; And thereupon the Avowant, or he that makes Cognizance ſhall have Iudgment for ſuch Arrearages, or ſo much thereof as the Goods or Cattle Diſtrained amount unto, together with full Coſts; and ſhall have Execution for the ſame by <hi>Fieri facias,</hi> or <hi>Elegit,</hi> or otherwiſe, as the Law ſhall Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if Iudgment in any of the Courts aforeſaid, be given upon Demurrer for the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vowant, or him that makes Cognizance for any Rent, the Court ſhall at the Prayer of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:151186:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->
Award a Writt to Inquire of the Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of ſuch Diſtreſs, and upon the Return there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of Iudgment ſhall be given for the Avowant, or him that makes Cognizance, as aforeſaid; For the Arrears Alledged to be behind in ſuch A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vowry or Cognizance if the Goods or Cattle ſo Diſtrained ſhall amount to the Value; And in Caſe they ſhall not amount to that Value, then for ſo much as the ſaid Goods or Cattle ſo Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrained amount unto, together with his full Coſts of Suit, and ſhall have like Execution as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That in all Caſes aforeſaid, where the Value of the Cattle Diſtrained, as aforeſaid, ſhall not be found to be to the Value of the Arrears Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrained for, that the Party to whom ſuch Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rears were Due, his Executors or Adminiſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors may from time to time Diſtrain again for the Reſidue of the ſaid Arrears.</p>
            <p>And whereas no Sheaves or Cocks of Corn, Looſe, or in the Straw, or Hay in any Barn or Granary, or in any Hovell, Stack or Rick can by the Law be Diſtrained, or otherwiſe ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cured for Rent, whereby Landlords are often<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times Deceived by their Tennants, who Sell their Corn, Grain and Hay to Strangers, and Remove the ſame from the premiſſes Chargable with ſuch Rent, and thereby avoid the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſame.</p>
            <p>Be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That for Remedying the ſaid Practice and Deceit, it ſhall and may from henceforth be Lawful to and for any Perſon or Perſons, having Rent Arrear and Due upon any Demiſe,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:151186:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
Leaſe, or Contract, to Seize and Secure any Sheaves or Cocks of Corn, or Corn Looſe, or in the Straw or Hay, lying, or being in any Barn or Granary, or upon any Hovell, Stack or Rick, or otherwiſe, upon any part of the Land or Ground Charged with ſuch Rent, and to Lock up, or Diſtrain the ſame in the place where the ſame ſhall be found, for, or in the Nature of a Diſtreſs, untill the ſame ſhall be Replevied upon good Security to be given to the Sheriff, as aforeſaid. And in Caſe ſuch Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs ſhall not be Replevied or owned within the ſpace of Eight Days next after the taking thereof, then the ſame to be Appraiſed and Sold according to the Laws and Cuſtoms of this Kingdom.</p>
            <p>Provided Nevertheleſs that ſuch Corn, Grain, or Hay ſo Diſtrained, as aforeſaid, be not Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved by the Perſon or Perſons Diſtraining to the Damage of the Owner thereof, out of the place where the ſame ſhall be found and Seized, but be kept there as Impounded, untill the ſame ſhall be Replevied or Sold, as aforeſaid. And in Caſe any Replevin ſhall be brought for ſuch Sheaf or Sheaves of Corn or Grain, or Hay, if the Plantiff in ſuch Replevin ſhall be Non-ſuit, either before or after Appearance, or a Verdict paſs againſt him, or Iudgment be gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven againſt him, upon Demurrer, as aforeſaid, in all ſuch Caſes ſuch Proceédings to be by Inquiſition or Fineing of the Iury at the Barr upon like Suggeſtion to be made in the Connuzance or Avowry, and like Execution in ſuch Caſes to be Awarded.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted, by the Authority
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:151186:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
aforeſaid, That upon any Pound-Breach, or Reſcue of Goods and Chattles Diſtrained for Rent, the Perſon or Perſons grieved thereby ſhall in a Special Action upon the Caſe, for the wrong thereby Suſtained, Recover his and their Treble Damages and Coſts of Suit, againſt the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fender or Offenders, in any ſuch Reſcue or Pound-Breach, any, or either of them, or againſt the Owners of the Goods Diſtrained, in Caſe the ſame be afterwards found to have come to his Vſe or Poſſeſſion.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:151186:5"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 33 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
